# **VILIUS DZEMYDA**

Front-End Web Developer

+353 85 838 5657 hello@viliusdzemyda.com www.viliusdzemyda.com

#### **PROFILE**

Strong technical and communication skills. More than six years of experience in building and maintaining client-side web applications. Good understanding of UI design patterns, user experience, technology stacks, development tools, and best practices. Open-minded, analytical, logical, able to grasp difficult concepts and good at troubleshooting.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development - (Feb 2019 – Present)

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, GitHub, Data management,
Agile development, Frameworks

# School of Technology and Business - Veisiejai, Lithuania

Maturity Certificate - (Sep 2001 – Jun 2004)

English, IT, Arts, Maths, Physics

# **SKILLS**

Communication, Problem Solving Responsive Web Design UX, SEO

### **TECH**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js Bulma, Bootstrap, SCSS Linux, CLI, Git, npm WordPress, Nuxt.js Netlify, Cloudways

# **EXPERIENCE**

(Jan 2017 – Present)

## Freelance

Navan, Ireland

(Apr 2015 – Nov 2015)

# **Purple Pod**

Navan, Ireland

(Jun 2011 – Feb 2014)

The DG Group / Snap Dunshaughlin, Ireland

# Web Developer

Plan, design and develop WordPress sites for clients. Setup domains, emails, migrate and backup data, configure servers. Support clients by phone and email. Design and develop Vue.js static sites and deploy to Netlify.

#### Front-End Developer

I converted multiple design mock-ups into fully functional templates for an online store. I was responsible for the design and development of WordPress sites, and daily maintenance.

### Web Developer

My primary task was to convert Photoshop mock-ups into fully functional websites. To prototype faster and save time, I built an in-house CSS framework and starter WordPress theme. I made old websites mobile-friendly, implemented responsive techniques, and tested for browser compatibility. Support clients by email.